Hello everyone, in the process of using Marvelous Designer, I don't know if you have used the
name line function, but through the name line function in Marvelous Designer, you can
make the necklace in the video and the sewing line effect in the previous one.
Next, let's learn how to add a name line.
Find the tool group of the name line in the 2D window.
The mouse mouse button is on the edit name line tool.
Click on the small scissors to read the entire menu.
The first tool is used to edit the name line that has been created.
So let's first learn how to add a name line.
The line section name line function is similar to the line division function.
When we select the line section name line tool,
it will stop the mouse on the line section.
It will use the straight line point as the basis to identify each line section.
Now we click on a line section.
In the 3D window, we can see that the name line has been added.
In the 2D window, the plum red highlight indicates that the name line has been created here,
and the name line will automatically be added to the symmetrical version.
Then we can click on other lines and add a name line to other lines.
Note that although these lines are related,
the name line created by using the line section name line is not related.
Because they are added one by one, they will not be automatically linked together.
If you want to delete the excess name line,
use the edit name line function to select the name line and press the delete key to delete it.
Or you can right-click when selecting a name line,
and select delete in the output menu.
It's the same.
Next, let's look at the free name line.
Free name line and free
name line are similar.
When using free name line, we can freely choose the starting and end points of the name line.
Click on the starting point,
and move the mouse to create the name line.
Click on the end point.
Then, let's look at the effect of creating a free name line using the free name line.
Click on the starting point.
Then go to the right position and click the end point
After creating, let's check the effect
Because free powder is a whole line
So this line is connected
So it is naturally connected at the corner
Then we delete these lines
Let's take a look at the last line
Powder line line
Powder line line tool
Will create a line along the powder line
So when we switch to this tool
All powder lines will be marked
When our mouse moves on a line with a powder line
There will also be a corresponding point at the other end
Move together
The operation method of this tool is similar to free powder line
It's just that it will follow the powder line
Also automatically create a powder line at the other end
Click the starting point in the same way
In the position where you want to create a powder line
Move mouse
Click the end point
Now we can see in the 3D window
Along this group of powder lines
There are powder lines on both sides
Finally, let's talk about
Some operations that can be done with the editing powder line tool
First use the editing powder line tool
We can adjust the starting point and end point of a powder line
If you want to adjust the end point
First you have to select this powder line
After selecting the powder line
Click the end point of this powder line
You can drag this end point
Use it to adjust the position of the powder line
After dragging the starting point
To the right position
Loosen the mouse and it's done
If you click and drag
It's the middle of the line
And not two end points
It's a whole line to move
We can also see it in the preview
The operation method of the powder line
And the operation method of the powder line
It's similar
After selecting the powder line
Right click
In the menu bar
There are some options
The first option is to select all
With the same attribute
After selecting this option
All and this powder line
Use the same powder line type of powder line
Will be selected
The powder line selected
Will be displayed in a high saturation plum red
The second option is to apply a new powder line
After selecting this option
In the powder line project
A new powder line type will be added
Then the powder line we selected
Will automatically use this default
New powder line type
About where to look at the powder line type
Or how to adjust
We'll talk about it later
The fourth option is to add the inner line in the powder line position
After choosing this option
It will follow the current position of the powder line
To automatically create an inner line
For example, here
The powder line has a certain diameter
Then the inner line is also based on this diameter
To create
Then we will see again
Use the edit powder line tool
After selecting a powder line
In the attribute editor
The corresponding settings
Here are the attributes that come out
All for the selected powder line
To be set
For example, you can modify the name of this powder line
Or apply it to a different powder line type
Then it's extension
Extension here
It will randomly open the opening and ending extension
When we choose to select the extension type
The powder line will automatically extend
To the other line of this line
If we cancel here
Extend to the beginning
Then the powder line will
According to its original
This line
All the way to the end of this line
That is to say
When we cancel the powder line
The powder line is created
With the line it is in
When we select the extension
If we select extension
It's like applying to the powder line
Or to the inner line
The powder line will automatically align
Okay, let's take a look
About the setting of the corner
First of all, the first option is the curve
When we select the curve
The corner will automatically
In the form of a curve
Instead of a sharp angle
Here we can set
The length of the curve
Next, let's take a look
The option of right angle corner
First of all, we need to pay attention to
The right angle corner
Can only work
On the powder line on the outer corner
When we select the right angle corner
In the corner position
It will automatically generate a 90 degree corner
Instead of extending to the banana position
The next one is the distance between the corners
In fact, it is the distance between the powder lines
The smaller the number
The closer the powder line
The larger the number
The farther the powder line
At present, the smallest distance between the corners
Can only be set to 0
Can not be set to negative
The last one is the turn
When the powder line is added to the line
If you select the turn
It will automatically turn
To the other side of this line
The powder line in the video
When we select the turn
It will turn to the other side of this inner line
And it is still connected
Then click on the name of the fabric window
In the drop-down menu
Find the top stitch
Switch to the line type
Then in the line type column
Choose a line type
In the property editor below
Will appear
The corresponding properties
In the property editor
We can open or save
Adjusted line type
Below can adjust the name of this line
The offset below
To the gap between this line
The larger the number
The farther the line from it
The farther the distance
The smaller the number
The closer the line to this line
Below we can switch
The name line type
When the name line type
Is the name line
It is just a sticker
Not a real 3D grid
The name line type
Is still visible
Is the OBJ name line
That is, the name line
If there is a real 3D grid
When we turn on the simulation
The name line will automatically hide
When we pause the simulation
The name line will be displayed again
Next is the name line specifications
First is the type of the name line
In the drop-down menu
We can find the type of the name line
Its name line row is Z
And more dense
Like this name line preset
The name line created
When on the name line
It will create along our line
And crossed two panels
In addition to the name line preset
The name line preset
Can also cross the panel
Add along the position of the name line
You can pause here
Try to switch
Different name line types
Through the length of the name line
We can control the length of the name line
In the direction of the add line
The width of the name line is
The width of the name line
This width does not mean the thickness of the line
But just the shape of the shape
Because the name line is a single loop
The line is made up of
If we set the diameter
Then the name line is single loop
There will be a diameter of the number we set
The structure like the left side
There will be no diameter between each loop
So we return the diameter to 0
The thickness of the line
Is used to control the thickness of the name line
The higher the number
The thicker the name line is
The lower the value
The thinner the name line
Because these names
Are all preset in the software
Next we will learn
How to define your own single loop
Name line type
Now we go back to the name line table
Add a name line type
And use the current name line
Add the name line to the sheet
Then click on the new one
This name line type
In the self-defined OBJ
Select the appropriate OBJ file
After clicking on the name line
The shape of the name line
Will be changed
After entering this
We will see that this shape is very small
So here we first
Increase its length
And the thickness of the line
After calculating the value
We will see that it is a loop
So we can continue
Increase its length
And the thickness of the line
To the value we think is appropriate
After this
Because we have set the name line
To the interval between the lines
This interval value is too small
As a result, after the name line is used
The excess part
Exceeds the position of the sheet
So now we want to increase the interval
So that the whole picture
Can be fully displayed
The interval at the bottom
Let's set it to 0
Actually the interval value
Not only can be set to 0
They can also be set to negative
Here we can set the interval to negative
So that the interval between the lines
Pass through each other
Form a complete chain
At this time we will notice that the name line
It has some problems with stretching and deformation
After clicking on the display clothing grid
We will notice
The place where the name line is more flat
Is the place where the grid is more smooth
The place where the name line will be broken
Is the place where it is attached
The grid is a bit crooked
This is because the name line
Is on top
If the fabric is stretched and deformed
Then the name line above it
Will also be stretched and deformed
So what we are going to solve now
Is the fabric problem
So now we switch to the window of the fabric
Find the fabric in this chain
Then in the physical properties
Of the attribute editor
Reduce the strength of the tail sand
The strength of the gold sand
And the tension of the corner line
So that the fabric will become easy to stretch
In order to avoid the wrinkle of the shadow
After opening the simulation
We will see that the damage effect is a little better
Then we increase the bending strength of the fabric
A little bit
After increasing the bending strength
The fabric will not bend easily
The panel will not be able to produce
A small wrinkle
And will not cause deformation
Because of the bending
After a short simulation
We will see that the name line
Has not been like before
There is a serious stretch deformation problem
We again
Increase the bending strength of the fabric
Now because the whole panel
Is a relatively smooth
And there is no wrinkled shape
So there is no deformation
In the name line above
Because the OBJ name line
It is a three-dimensional structure
But it does not produce a collision
So we have to replace it
Use the conflict thickness of the panel
To achieve
A collision with other panels
In order to avoid the name line
And other panels
Here we will
Increase the conflict thickness of this panel
To avoid the connection
Between the name line and other panels
After adjusting the name line
The conflict thickness of this panel
And the material used in this panel
After the physical properties
In order to hide this piece of fabric
We set the transparency of the fabric to 0
So that we can see
The name line
Next, let's take a look at
Some problems with the self-defined OBJ
Sometimes we use
Our own OBJ pattern
As the name line pattern
We will see that it has some
Problems with the surface
This problem is mainly because
The OBJ pattern
Is different from the units
Used in Marvelous Designer
Now we use this OBJ
As a virtual model
We will take a look at
The form of the unit
In Marvelous Designer
After that, we will see
If we use the name line
Of the unit in the software
Then this shape is very small
We need to
Make a transformation
In Marvelous Designer
By the ratio of the property editor
We can actually compare it
With the name line
After the size is right
When we select the selection
First, we need to cancel
The selection and the selection
Of all the models
We only need to select
All the virtual models
Because this virtual model
Is the OBJ that we just selected
Remember to cancel
All the stickers and sub-folders
Then, based on the need
Choose whether to export the UV image
Select mm from the bottom unit
Then click OK to export
Now we select the second OBJ as the shape of the line, and then we will find that there is no breakage.
Ok, let's go back to the previous line type and its properties.
Below is the material setting of the line, including the material type of the line and its specific material sticker.
We can choose to open and import here.
After that, it is the environment setting for this line type.
First of all, you can choose this kind of line, they are displayed on the front or back of the grid, or all.
If I choose the back, then the line is only displayed on the back of the grid, the front is not visible.
If you choose all, then this line will be displayed in the front and back of the board at the same time.
Below we can choose this kind of line type.
The number of lines, the higher the number, the more lines.
Below we can set the gap between the line and the line.
We can choose to use preset values ​​or manually fill the gap.
Below we can set the 3D effect of the line.
After opening the 3D option, we will create the line effect according to the position of the current created line.
The higher the strength, the more obvious the line effect will be, the more rough it will be.
Below we can set the thin line effect of the line.
The higher the value, the thicker the line.
The smaller the value, the thinner the line effect.
You can set the value according to the need.
Here we will see that the line copied from the number of lines is of the same effect.
Next, let's learn how to change the line type used in a line type or add multiple lines near a line.
First, when we choose a line type, the line type used will be displayed in orange.
When we choose a line type or multiple lines, click the application button next to other line types.
We can apply this type of line type to the selected line type.
Next, let's see how to apply multiple lines near a line type at the same time.
First, we can click the Add button at the top to add a new type of line type.
Set the value according to the need.
Or select the line type that has been created.
After selecting the type of line type, repeat the previous operation.
Use the line type of line type.
Add a new type of line type to the selected line type.
In the three-dimensional window, you can see that there are two lines near this line type.
Use the edit line tool to click the line type with multiple line types.
A list will pop up.
You can choose a specific line type according to the name and edit its properties.
Finally, let's learn about the function of the line type classification table.
First is the list at the top.
Click Add to add a default line type.
After selecting a type of line type, click Copy.
You can copy a line type with the same properties.
Use the select line tool to select one or more lines.
Click Apply.
You can apply a new default line type on these lines.
Then you can change its specific properties.
Click Delete unused.
It will automatically delete all the line types that are not applied to the line type.
In addition to these functions at the top,
After selecting a type of line type,
Right-click and there will be a corresponding menu bar.
First of all, in the right-click menu bar, the first option is to delete.
But if this type of line type is applied to the line type, it cannot be deleted.
Now we directly add a new type of line type.
And this type of line type has not been applied to other lines.
In the right-click menu bar, you can choose to delete.
In the right-click menu bar, the second option is to rename.
After choosing to rename, you can directly enter the name of the line type here.
Double-click on the line type name and you can rename the line type.
In the right-click menu bar, the third option is to reset.
If you choose to reset, the selected type of line type will be reset to default.
In the right-click menu bar, the fourth option is to copy and the top copy is the same function.
When we select one or more types of line type,
Select the merge to default line type in the right-click menu bar.
Will merge all these line types and apply a default line type setting.
How to apply and adjust the relevant content of the line type is over.
See you in the next video.
Bye bye.